Preliminary Inventory of the Liviu Floda Papers, 1935-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
Liviu Floda Papers,
1935-1996
95023
Floda, Liviu
83 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (35.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Scripts and sound recordings of Radio Free Europe broadcasts to Romania, and related correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to Romanian politics, society and culture, the status of civil liberties in Romania, and activities of Romanians abroad.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Radio Free Europe; Radio broadcasting--Romania; Romanians in foreign countries; Romania--Politics and government--20th century; Romania--Social conditions; Romania--Civilization; Romanians in foreign countries; Civil rights--Romania; Romania; United States--Foreign relations; Phonotapes
Preliminary Inventory
- Telex messages, 1974 (Box 1.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1974
- Telex messages, 1975 (Box 2.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1975
- Telex messages, 1976 (Box 3.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1976 (Box 4.)
- Telex messages, 1977-1978 (Box 5.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1977 (Box 6.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1978 (Box 7.)
- Telex messages, 1979-1980 (Box 8.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1979 (Box 9.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1980 (Box 10.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1981 (Box 11.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1981 (Box 12.)
- Telex messages, 1981
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1982 (Box 13-14.)
- Telex messages, 1982-1983 (Box 15.)
- Telex messages, 1983-1984 (Box 16.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1983 (Box 17-18.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1984 (Box 19-20.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1985 (Box 21-22.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1986 (Box 23-24.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1987 (Box 25-26.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1989 (Box 27-28.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1990 (Box 29-30.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1991 (Box 31.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1992 (Box 32.)
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1993 (Box 33.)
- Sound Recordings (34-41)
  Lists benzilor mici (nu "casetelor"), cuprinzând programe difuzate în a doua jumătate a deceniului 1960 şi începutul anilor T1970 - 5 inches)
  Lista benzilor medium size (7 inches). Interviuri difuzate de Radio Europa Libera (Radio Free Europe) la
  - Voice of America program scripts, 1994 (Box 34.)
  - Sound recordings of radio broadcasts
  - Sound recordings of radio broadcasts (Box 35-41.)
- Bishop Valerian Trifa case, 1979-1980 (Box 42.)
- Virgil Popescu hunger strike, 1973
- "American Scene" and "Panoramas" programs, 1987
- "U.S. Reports," 1973
- American-Romanian Academy annual congress essays, 1981-1987
- Munich-New York correspondence, 1976-1987 (Box 43.)
- Paul Goma opposition to Romanian regime, 1978 (Box 44.)
- Viata Noastra publications, 1964-1993
- Micro-Magazin publications, 1973-1991
- "Panoramas" programs, 1968 (Box 45.)
- "Panoramas" programs, 1972-1973
- Telex messages, 1988-1990
- Radio Free Europe program scripts, 1988 (Box 46-47.)
- Radio Actualitatea (Box 48.)
- "Sixty Years in the Service of the Press" (Viata Noastra columns)
- "Romanian Experts and Writers about Danube," 1974
- "America Seen with the Greyhound Buses," 1966
- "Expo 67" broadcasts, 1967
- Human rights issues
- Sorbonne University paper, 1987
- Romanians in the West (Box 49.)
- Romanians in American cultural life
- Miscellaneous, 1974-1994 (Box 50.)
- Romanians in different fields in the U.S.A. (Box 50-51.)
- Stagebills (Box 52.)
- Commercial sound recordings
- Devis Grebu postcards of New York
- Biographical data
- Press identification documents
- Autographed photographs of Mariana Nicolescu (Box 53-54.)
- Phonotape reels of Radio Free Europe broadcasts (Box 54-55.)
- List of phonotape cassettes of Radio Free Europe broadcasts (Box 55.)
- Phonotape cassettes of Radio Free Europe broadcasts (Box 56-66.)